理解融合
欢迎关注微博@UUU字幕组，获取最新熟肉信息！
出品
UUU字幕组
翻译
Huksy
校对
右翼部鸣明
特效
presisco
压制
presisco/SG
然后我们就进入表演
And then we go into the tricks.
好
All right.
但我真心觉得	[遛狗]那招
But I really think we should save the dogwalker
应该留到下次
for next time.
这是我们的第一印象 得搞得浮夸点
This is our first impression. We gotta go big.
而且我们也应该赶紧行动 免得她们怀疑
And we should go soon, too, before they get suspicious.
这俩人表现的非常可疑哇
Those two are acting very suspicious.
我们要问问他们在干啥吗
Should we ask them what's going on?
我不能
I can't.
好吧
Right.
史蒂文 紫晶
Steven, Amethyst!
你们是不是有啥事准备告诉我们呀
Is there something you'd like to tell us?
嘛你们应该知道我们最近在副宝宝基地有一场
So you guys know how we recently had an epic showdown
史诗级别的决战
in the beta kindergarten.
你们也知道 在那时候 我们打败了铁石英
And you know that during it, we beat Jasper.
但是你们知道
But do you know...
谁打败了她吗
who beat Jasper?
你俩吗
You two?
橄榄石
Peridot.
她们没猜到
It didn't land.
直接切入正题 切入正题
Pick it back up. Pick it back up!
咳咳 我们这有个人希望与你们见见面
Ahem! We have someone we'd like you to meet!
好啊 就让我们见见这位神秘的陌生人吧
All right, let's meet this mysterious stranger.
嘿呀 我是烟晶
Heya. I'm Smoky Quartz.
见到你们真是愉快
Nice to meet ya.
-啥-噢
-What?!-Oh!
别急着提起吓掉的袜子
Don't bother putting your socks back on,
精彩的还在后头呢
'cause I'm about to knock 'em off again!
现在 你们应该能看出我是怎么打败铁石英的了
Now, you guys can see exactly how I beat Jasper.
这一招我喜欢叫	[与狗漫步]
This is a little trick I like to call "Walk the Dog"!
等等 谁来解释下这一切
Wait! Explain everything!
这招叫	[与狗慢跑]
This one's called "Jog the Dog"!
哎呀 哈 这招叫
Whoops! Ha! Uh, this one is called
[遛狗只是我白天的工作
"Dog Walking's Just My Day Job
直到面试结果出来为止]
Till I Finally Get That Callback"!
石榴 帮个忙
Garnet, a little help.
-嗯嗯嗯 -红纹玛瑙
Mnh-mnh-mnh!  Sardonyx!
你知道室内玩儿武器的规定的
You know the rules about weapons in the house.
大多数情况可以使用 但是有一些例外
Mostly allowed, really,but with some exceptions.
见到你真是荣幸
Oh, what a pleasure it is to meet you.
你已经留下了很深的"印象"了
You've made quite the impression already.
你看 墙上那边有一个 还有那里......
In fact, there's one in the wall over there and there and...
呃 抱歉 看来刚才我有点控计不住我记己
Uh, sorry. Looks like I got  bit carried away.
我会 呃 收敛一点
I can, uh...reel it in.
快停下
Stop!
说真的 别再这么做了
But really, please -- stop.
你刚才的表演真是太棒了
Your act is tremendous.
但是给你展示的舞台太小了
But your stage is too small.
我们需要更大的空间来了解一下彼此
We need some space to get to know each other.
比如一个...更无限的地方
Somewhere a bit more... infinite.
你在神庙里有一个专属房间?
You have a room in the temple?
只要我存在 它就存在
It exists as long as  I exist.
现在...我...进去了
And here...I...am!
快来 别害羞
Come now, don't be shy.
我现在嘛都看不见
I can't see nothing in here.
是的你看不见任何东西 亲爱的
You cannot see anything, my darling --
因为演出还没开始呢
because the show hasn't started yet!
演出?
Show?
来自神庙深处的超自然房间的直播
Live, from a metaphysical room deep in the temple,
欢迎来到"今夜玛瑙秀"
it's "Sardonyx Tonight"!
大家晚上好
Good evening, everybody!
今晚我们迎来了一个全新的融合体
We have a brand-new fusion with us tonight.
我简直要兴奋到要碎掉
I'm so excited, I could just shatter!
掌声欢迎--烟晶
Everyone welcome Smoky Quartz!
那么快告诉我
So tell me, literally,
所有关于你的事
everything there is to know about yourself.
不要跳过任何有料的细节哦
And do not skip out on any of the juicy details.
嘛 我挺喜欢在宝宝基地长距离漫步
Well, I like, uh, long walks through the kindergarten.
实际上 我就是在那里成型的
actually,that's where I stored up became me.
然后 呃 嘭 --打败了铁石英
And, uh, pow --beat Jasper.
哦 就是那个铁石英 不断在宝宝基地出没
Oh, that Jasper, always running 'round kindergartens
四处捣乱
and causing trouble.
果然最后结局不好呢
Boy, that didn't quite work out for her.
我猜她得回学前班了 是吧 各位
Guess she should go back to preschool, am I right, folks?
是啊
Yeah.
她在与一个堕转宝石的融合时完全发疯了
She lost her mind in a corrupted fusion.
我想你可以说她进行了一次...短暂的融合
I guess you could say she had a...short fuse?
观众挺友好,是吧?
Easy crowd, huh?
哪里找来的?
Where'd you get 'em?
我变出来的
I made them myself.
但烟晶 我想我们真正好奇的是...
But, Smoky, I think what we really want to know is...
你究竟是谁
who are you?
烟晶...是谁
Who is...Smoky...Quartz?
呃 嘛 现在加上战斗的时候
Uh, well, between the fight and now, yeah,
我总共才存在了 大概 十分钟 所以 呃
I've only really existed for, like, 10 minutes, so, uh...
我 我不知道
I-I don't know.
但是我知道怎么做这个
But I do know how to do this! Uh...
这招叫	[裹在纸尿裤里的忧郁婴儿]
This one's called "Sad Baby in a Diaper"!
对 溜溜球
Yes, the yo-yo.
看过 体验过 喜欢过
Seen it,lived it,loved it!
但是你有其他的技能吗
But what about the rest of your game?
我的把戏哪有扑克牌那么多啦
I ain't exactly a deck of cards here.
哦 我倒可以舔到我的胳膊肘
I  can lick my elbow.
现在我可有三个咧
I have three of them now.
现在由赞助商讲两句话,广告之后马上回来
We'll be right back after a word from our sponsor!
听着 小烟 让我们来一场融合体之间的对话
Listen, Smoky, let's talk -- fusion to fusion.
你的溜溜球确实不错 但我更想了解你本人
That's a nice yo-yo, but I want to know the yo-you.
啊
What?
小烟 你除了溜溜球之外肯定
Smoky, there's bound to be way more to you than just...
还有更多
a yo-yo.
你是一个融合体
You're a fusion.
你是充满了惊喜的
You're full of surprises!
只是你现在还不知道罢了
You just don't know it yet.
红玛瑙拿铅笔的姿势源自脱口秀主持人David Letterman
对,对啊,惊喜就是你不知道的事嘛
Yeah. Yeah, I guess that is how surprises work.
我想到了!
I've got it!
每个融合都会获得一些新的东西
Every fusion gets something new --
这里的尖叫声是著名的"Wilhelm scream"
比如一种新能力,或者新武器
a new power, a new weapon.
比如悠悠球?
Like a yo-yo?
对,但比那好
Yes, but better.
我们来找找你身上有什么新的地方
Let's find out what's new about you.
欢迎回来!
And welcome back!
那些卡通人物肯定让你
Don't those cartoon characters
超想买她们的周边对吧
make you want to buy those products?
但愿如此,不然我就没钱赚了
I sure hope so,or else I'd be off air.
今晚我们为你准备了一个新环节
We have a new segment for you all tonight.
没错,各位
That's right, everyone.
现在进入"打-个-鸟"
It's time to Hit That Bird!
欧珀在天空塔的冒险当中
During Opal's adventures at the sky spire,
她用弓箭打掉了一群怪物鸟
she took down a flock ofbird monsters with her bow.
我们来看看你有没有她的"珀"力吧
Let's see if you've got her "opalescent" aim.
你怎么想,小烟?
What do you say, Smoky?
你准备好打个鸟了吗?
Are you ready to Hit That Bird?
哦,啊,这个,弓箭也算一种悠悠球是吧?
Oh! Ah, well, a bow is kind of like a yo-yo, right?
除了上面的弦方向不一样还有...
Except if the string went this a ways and...
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
现在开始,如何?
Let's start, shall we?
时间可不等人哦!
Time is an impatient thing!
哦!
Oh!
啊哦,时间到
Uh-oh, time's up.
我们来看看
Let's see.
分数加起来是
The score tallies to...
一,二,三...
one, two, three...
零分
zero.
我想我真是持盾呢,哈
Guess I'm a real bow-zo, ha.
我们向前进入下一个环节如何啊,各位?
What do you say we move on to the next segment, everybody?
我们到了!
Here we are!
我把这个环节叫...
I call this segment...
你喜欢吗,小个子?
You Like That, Little Man?
因为人人都喜欢往期回顾嘛
'Cause everybody loves a callback.
她没有真的出演本集
She's not actually in this episode.
这样还要付她工资吗
Do we still have to pay her?
要?好吧
Yes? Fair enough.
好,融合之后能力会提升,这已是公开的秘密了
Now, it's no secret that us fine fusions pack an extra punch.
苏纪石因其强有力
But Sugilite is a standout
的击打能力而鹤立鸡群
for being a heavy hitting powerhouse.
但是也许你有一些比苏纪石更厉害的招数?
But maybe you've got something to top Sugilite's swing?
嗯,也许吧?
Mmm, maybe?
用这个槌来击打垫子
Just hit the base with this mallet,
来看看你能力有多强
and we'll see how you measure up.
好
Okay.
你就这水平?
That all you got?
天了
Gosh.
哦!非常接近了!
Ooh! Very close.
加上一些旋转动作会更好哦
An extra spin around always helps me!
旋转动作,是吗?
An extra spin, huh?
好吧
Okay.
哈哈,想得美!
Ha ha! Nice try!
啥!
What?!
再来一次!
One more time!
你...啥也...不是!
You...ain't...nothing!
嗯,好
Hmm, yes.
确实有什么不对的地方
Something just isn't hitting right here.
也许你的强壮
Maybe you're just strong...
♪表现在别处
♪In a different way
我们很快回来
We'll find out in just a moment.
放出场音乐,乔治
Play us over to stage right,Jorge!
呃...
Uh...
好了,别担心那些观众
Okay, don't worry about that crowd.
也别想乔治了,就只有你和我
Don't worry about Jorge.It's just you and me.
对啊,没问题
Yeah, no duh.
那个...谁是乔治啊?
Actually...who's Jorge?
小烟,你不要隐藏实力
Smoky,you're holding out on me.
我准备好看你的能力了
I'm ready to see your main event.
啊,我也是
Ah, you and me both.
好,亚历山大石有喷火的能力
Now, Alexandrite has a throat full of flames.
不造这是不是她嗓音沙哑的原因
Whether that's the cause of her raspy voice
这个先放一边
is up for debate,
但是毫无疑问的是她攻击时--
but there's no room for questions when she attacks --
会吐出烈焰!
exhaling a burning blaze!
所以我把这个环节叫"火之吐息"
So I call this segment"Breath of Fire."
"Breath of Fire"也是"Super Nintendo"上的一款RPG游戏的名字
玛瑙,我不确定啊
Sardonyx, I don't know.
来吧,小烟
Come on, Smoky.
站上舞台试试看
Step up and see if you can spit
你能不能吐出一些火之元素
some elemental chaos at the target.
我们似乎遇到了一些魔法故障
We seem to experiencing some magical difficulties.
但是别换台哦
But don't change the channel.
史蒂文和紫晶一定有些共同点
There must be some common thread between Steven and Amethyst
成倍体现在他们的融合上
that's heightened by their fusion.
我不确定啊,玛,我想,零加零不还是零吗
I don't know, Sards, I guess,uh, zero plus zero equals zero.
他们想到一块去的事,他们做到一块去的事
Something they both think.Something they both do.
人说负负不得正嘛--
They say two wrongs don't make a right --
我不就是典型的例子吗?
I guess I'm living proof that that's true!
我就是一个大个儿的失败的...
I'm just one big super wrong...
除了悠悠什么都不会的家伙
...good-for-nothing dud with a yo-yo.
他们想给我们留下好印象!
They want to impress us!
他们已经准备了一个早上了
They were planning this all morning.
我们抢了他们的风头!
We hijacked their show!
我过于兴奋了!
I was excited!
这不是我们俩的事!
It's not about us!
哈?
Huh?
发生啥事?!
What's happening?!
是红纹玛瑙!
It's Sardonyx!
如果她不在这里,这个房间就不能存在!
If she's not here,the room can't exist!
石榴!
Garnet!
珍珠!
Pearl!
哈?
Huh?
抱歉降落有些颠簸
Sorry for the rough landing.
-你在说什么呢?!-简直太精彩了!
-What are you talking about?!-That was amazing.
哦,紫晶
Oh, Amethyst!
你真是为他树立了一个好榜样!
You've been such a good influence on him!
其实他是我的榜样了
It's kind of the other way around.
你们可告诉我们悠悠能当钩爪使
You didn't tell us that yo-yo can grapple.
悠悠能做很多事情呢
It can do so much stuff!
等下,你是把它当绳圈还是鞭子用?
Wait. So do you use it like a lasso or a flail?
-比鞭子好多了!-它是个玩具!
-It's better than a flail.-It's a toy!
真是想不到
It's so unexpected.
把当时情况实况转播一下
Give us the play-by-play.
我们当时在那...
So, there we were...